A Guide to the Reed Island Iron Company, 1880-1896
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Reed Island Iron Company Ledgers, 1880-1896
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2012-081
0.7 cu. ft. 2 boxes
The collection includes customer account, invoice, and workman's hours ledgers from the Reed Island Iron Company. Records dates from 1880-1896, during most of the known active period of the company (c.1880-c.1906).
Reed Island Iron Company. (Pulaski County, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Reed Island Company Ledgers were acquired by Special Collections prior to 2009.
Historical Note
The Reed Island Furnace was first operated by the Reed Island Iron Company, in Reed Island, Virginia (near Allisonia), beginning around 1881.The furnace itself was in Pulaski County, while the company was based in Wythe County. By 1898, the furnace and the company appeared to be the property and works of the Virginia Iron, Coal, and Coke Company, who ran the furnace until about 1906.
Sources:
Directory to the Iron and Steel Works of the United States. Philadelphia: The American Iron and Steel Association, 1890. Available online.
Supplement to the Directory of Iron and Steel Works of the United States. Philadelphia: The American Iron and Steel Association, 1900. Available online.
Scope and Content
The collection includes customer account, invoice, and workman's hours ledgers from the Reed Island Iron Company. Records dates from 1880-1896, during most of the known active period of the company (c.1880-c.1906).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series, both of which are arranged chronologically.
Series I: Customer Account & Invoice Ledgers consists of ledgers dating from 1880 through 1893. The majority records are customer accounts (eight of nine ledgers in this series) and include names and transactions, as well as amounts due and paid. The remaining book is a list of customer invoices. There is some overlap among the ledgers and they do not cover all months for the 13 year period.
Series II: Workman's Hours Ledgers contains small booklets from 1886-1896. These ledger include lists of the names of workers for a given month, tracking their hours. There is no apparent overlap between the ledgers and they do not cover the entire time period between August 1886 and April 1896.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Reed Island Iron Company Receipts, 1894-1896. Ms2009-040. Finding aid available online.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Reed Island Iron Company. (Pulaski County, Va.)
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Pulaski County (Va.)
Contents List
- Series I: Customer Account & Invoice Ledgers, 1880-1893
  - November-December 1880 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - June-August 1881, 1888 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - 1882-? (Box-folder 2-1)
  - November-December 1883 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - June-October 1887 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - October 1888-March 1889 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - December 1888-April 1889 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - November 1893 (Box-folder 2-2)
  - 1893 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Series II: Workman's Hours Ledgers, 1886-1896
  - August 1886-April 1888 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - February-April 1889 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - January-March 1890 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - June-July 1891 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - November 1892-January 1898 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - February 1895-April 1896 (Box-folder 1-7)